Email: <u>brycetham@gmail.com</u> Website: http://www.brycetham.com

## **OVERVIEW**

I am a graduate student pursuing a master's degree at Stanford University studying computer science with depth in human-computer interaction. I have experience in several programming languages, most notably Python and Java, and also in web development and database design. In the past, I have been an intern at the UCI Office of Information Technology as well as a research assistant at the UCI Institute for Software Research. I am interested in software engineering, computational problem-solving, and data informatics.

# **EDUCATION**

## M.S. in Computer Science, Class of 2019

Stanford University

Depth in Human-Computer Interaction

## B.S. in Computer Science, Class of 2017

University of California, Irvine

Specialization (Double) in Information & Algorithms 3.993 GPA, Summa Cum Laude, Honors in ICS

# **SKILLS** (by order of strength)

**Programming**: Python, Java

**Database Design**: SQL/MySQL, Informatica

Web Development: HTML/CSS, JavaScript

# **EXPERIENCE**

## AR Applications Research Assistant | UCI Institute for Software Research

April 2016 – August 2017

- Worked with Dr. Walt Scacchi on an IoT-based augmented reality project for smart workers in advanced manufacturing.
- Researched training techniques and interactive game-based systems to illustrate conceptual augmented learning.
- Wrote design documents, attributed directed graph models, and problem specifications for the manufacturing simulation.
- Created a prototype illustrating the conceptual implications of augmented reality in the context of real manufacturing settings.

## **Data Warehouse Developer Intern** | *UCI Office of Information Technology*

April 2015 – August 2017

- Compared and write reports for hundreds of tables during the company's database migration away from Talend.
- Developed dozens of Informatica ETL mappings and sessions as part of the legacy ODS conversion.
- Updated the Data Warehouse website with new content, including resolving security issues caused by SQL injection.
- Upgraded the online query-by-example ad-hoc tool in the DWH BLISS Enhancement project with various functionality additions.

## Technology Chair | Circle K International

April 2015 – March 2016

- Managed content and resources for members including general information, weekly updates, calendar events, and media.
- Developed new features and tools for the website such as a personal events portal and a smart announcements system.
- Managed a group of 4 students in organizing the club's first Technology Internship Program.
- Received the Distinguished Appointed Board Officer award for demonstrating excellent achievement in service.

### Lab Tutor | Donald Bren School of ICS

September 2014 – March 2015

- Tutored over 50 students in various ICS courses including Programming with Software Libraries and Intermediate Programming.
- Wrote pedagogical materials as resources for future students and proctored/facilitated in-lab examinations.

# **PROJECTS** (see website for full list)

#### Ocean Waves (Programmer/Designer)

January 2017

Ocean Waves is a game about a young girl named Ocean who strives to make the world a happier place by waving at the depressed denizens of her nearby park.

Completed for: Global Game Jam 2017; Programmed in: C#, Unity

#### **Bubble Buddy** (*Programmer/Designer*)

April 2016

Bubble Buddy is a web-based virtual communication companion designed for young children with autism who struggle with communication, identifying emotions, and learning by interacting with them using typical everyday conversation.

Completed for: Autism App Jam 2016; Programmed in: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MEAN stack; Awards: Winner (2nd Place), Hype Award

#### **Fabflix** (*Programmer*)

January 2016 – March 2016

Fabflix is a web-based interface that allows customers to browse/search for movie information, add interesting movies to their shopping cart, and check out.

Completed for: Project in Databases and Web Applications; Programmed in: Java, HTML, CSS, MySQL, JavaScript, Bootstrap

#### **UC Irvine Circle K Website** (*Programmer/Administrator*)

April 2015 – March 2016

The UC Irvine Circle K Website utilizes key web development techniques and open-source software solutions to create a reliable and robust website as a resource hub for members and a means of organizing club secretarial information.

Completed for: Circle K International; Programmed in: HTML, CSS, MySQL, JavaScript, PHP, Bootstrap; Awards: Outstanding Club Website (1st Place)